Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
MAN: When I think back to that day.
small details stick in my mind.
Things I said.
The look on people's faces.
They wanted to wipe us
from the face of the Earth.
But we kept asking ourselves "Why?"
After all the centuries
of mindless cruelty.
maybe we shouldn't
have been surprised.
Are we really so different?
There's evil inside of us all.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
Hey. Sophia. it’s me.
You never pick up.
I wanted to talk before I leave.
Your sponsor called. She says
you haven’t been to your meetings.
I’m worried about you.
I’ll be spending the night
at the observatory.
Could you please call me back?
Call me. Bye.
(TATTOO NEEDLE WHIRRS)
(MACHINE WHIRRS)
Hi.
All right?
(STICK TAPS)
Thanks. Bye.
WAR OF THE WORLDS
I.R.A.M Observatory
French Alps
Every song in the world
at your fingertips.
I can never decide what to play.
La paralysie du choix.
Choice paralysis. I have it
when I go to the hypermarket.
There's 100 different options.
I just want toothpaste.
(KEYBOARD CLACKS)
Have you seen this?
What's the source?
(TAPS KEYBOARD. BEEP)
Ross 128.
Can you check the frequency?
Um...153.26 gigahertz.
So high? That can't be right.
That's what it says.
Can you sonify the signal?
(KEYBOARD CLACKS)
(PULSATING ON MONITOR)
(PULSATING CONTINUES)
Could be a satellite.
I'll check with ESA.
(PULSATING CONTINUES)
"No registered satellite
in that band-pass."
Is there a pulsar out there?
No. there is no pulsar
at those coordinates.
And the frequency's too high.
(KEYBOARD CLACKS)
What's that?
The signal that Arecibo
picked up last year.
You know.
the one from Ross 128-B.
It's the same.
Yeah. but it's a lot stronger.
So what are we seeing?
What is it?
There's no naturally
occurring phenomena
that can produce
a signal like this.
Not in that frequency.
Where would you put it
on the Rio scale?
I don't know.
Six...maybe seven.
Put out an ATEL.
We need someone else
to verify it.
And contact ALMA.
Ask them to take a look at it.
(PULSATING)
Johannes!
Sorry.
(PULSATING CONTINUES)
(PULSATING GROWS LOUDER)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(SIGHS)
(PULSATING CONTINUES)
And?
ALMA confirms the signal.
They're getting the same readings.
They're flipping out.
Phase it up again.
Are you really sure
it can't be a pulsar?
I already checked. This is real.
What if we're wrong?
I'll look ridiculous.
We're not wrong. Catherine.
Make the call.
MAN: (ON PHONE) Hello...
Hi. This is...Catherine Durand
from the Institut
de Radioastronomie Millimetrique (IRMA).
I believe
we have detected evidence...
of extra-terrestrial life.
WEST LONDON
No way. That is not your breakfast.
-I'm late.
College doesn't start till nine.
-I'm meeting some friends.
Okay. take a banana.
Eating a banana
is your answer to everything.
Looks sore.
You hate it. don't you?
-It's your arm.
Are you going to tell Dad?
Maybe we'll wait till he gets home.
Go meet your friends.
Why aren't you dressed for school?
Said I'd call Dad
Conference Centre
North-Eastern France
Hey. buddy. how are you doing?
Yeah. is Mum okay?
Yeah.
Yeah. No. I can't talk to her now
'cause I'm just checking in.
Tell her I'll call her later. okay?
All right. okay. yeah.
Cheers. buddy. Okay.
Say hello to Em for me. Bye.
Hey.
How're you doing?
Good.
Madeline Clairmont.
MAN: Increasing the amplitude
of the stimulation current
DEPARTMENT OF NEUROBIOLOGY
UNIVERSITY COLLEGE. LONDON
and hyper-activation of the primary somatosensory
and pre-motor cortex.
This is direct evidence
that an induced current
contributes most
to corticospinal
pathway excitation.
So. actually...
raising the stimulation amplitude
would increase
the amount of neurons firing
and result in a larger response.
as we've just witnessed.
(MOBILE PHONE VIBRATES)
Excuse me. am I boring you?
Hmm? Maybe we should fire
a few neurons into your brain
just to get the juices flowing.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
We can make sense of this
through our targeting
of diverse neuronal structures
by two half segments.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRS.
INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
CATHERINE: The signal was detectable
for exactly 23 hours and 56 minutes.
One sidereal day.
One complete rotation of the Earth.
MAN: Is there
any significance in that?
We don't know.
You are part
of the METI initiative.
You've been sending messages
into space?
We send music.
The idea is that music would act
as a universal language.
But if they don't have ears.
they won't be able to hear it.
so we encoded the entire message
in a binary system
of two alternating frequencies.
pulsing 125 times per second.
(MURMURING)
Could this be a response?
If it is. it's in a language
that we don't understand.
The electromagnetic waves were
transmitted across a vast distance
with virtually no attenuation.
What does that mean?
It means that the power source
that generated the signal
is greater
than we can even conceive.
(MURMURING)
Does this mean
that they're a threat?
There's no evidence
to suggest that.
But surely it would be equally wrong
to assume they aren't a threat.
Dr Durand. what do we know?
Two years ago. we discovered
an exoplanet orbiting Ross 128.
The planet is in a habitable zone
and it may be able to support life.
But that's all we know.
(MURMURING)
Why are we detecting
this signal now?
We can't say for sure.
Perhaps they were...
looking for us.
(MURMURING)
Thank you. Perhaps you can
leave us for a minute.
Yes. sir.
Doctor? Colonel Mokrani.
I’m your military liaison.
Nice to meet you.
What just happened in there?
I think you scared them.
(BEEPING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(MESSAGE ALERTS)
NEWSREADER: We're now heading
over live to Brussels.
where representatives
from the European Space Agency
have been locked in talks since
the early hours of the morning.
MAN (ON MONITOR):
On Wednesday. at approximately
2300 hours Universal Time.
Dr Catherine Durand of the Institut
de Radioastronomie Millimetrique
detected a powerful signal
originating from an area
close to the star Ross 128.
All the evidence suggests
that the signal is indicative
of intelligent
extra-terrestrial life.
I hope this discovery is something
that will unite the human race.
Perhaps. we will see now
that we are far more alike
than we are different.
(People Chatter. Children Laugh)
CALAIS. FRANCE
Hey. what is it?
Do you ski?
- What? Do I ski?
- Yes.
You work in the mountains.
so I was thinking it’s possible.
Well. I used to.
but I haven’t for a long time.
- You okay?
- Yes.
I hate these things.
My men are here to secure the site.
You must tell me if we get in your way.
Don’t worry. I will.
- Catherine.
- Hey.
How did it go in Brussels?
-It was okay.
Can you believe this?
Hey. Dad.
Oh. hi.
(SIGHS) You heading off again?
I'm gonna be sleeping at the office
while this thing plays out.
So what aren't they telling us?
Should we be concerned?
There's nothing to tell.
They detected a signal.
Well. when the government
tells you not to panic.
that's when you gotta buy a rifle
and head for the hills.
You'd shoot yourself in the foot.
(ZIPS BAG)
You'd be lying there.
hoping the evil government
comes and rescues you.
Do you want me to open that?
Oh. I can open a bottle of wine.
Have you spoken to your mum?
She's fine.
Are you in tomorrow night?
Jack said he'd drop by
with the rest of my stuff.
What am I supposed to say to him?
I don't know.
Try nice. polite conversation.
I'm sure you'll figure it out.
You don't want me to stick one on him
because he dumped you. do you?
Is that supposed
to make me feel better?
I'll call you.
Okay.
(DOOR CLOSES)
You should come out for
the product launch. Vegas is crazy.
Yeah. it's difficult for me
to be away from home for too long.
Oh. I thought you said your daughter
is coping much better now.
Yes. she is. She is. but...
Then come to Vegas.
It will be fun.
Shall I get another bottle?
No. you know what? It's late.
But you could invite me
back to your room.
Or perhaps it's a bad idea.
Yes. sir?
-	The bill. please.
-	Of course.
(PHONE LINE TRILLS)
Come on. Sophia.
Answer your phone.
(MOBILE PHONE VIBRATES)
(SIGHS)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Go!
(BOTH PANT)
(HORN HONKS)
(SOFTLY) Go. go. go!
Quickly.
(METAL CLANKS)
Go. go.
Hey! Hey!
Go. go!
Under the truck! Come on!
No! No. no...
Please. please. don't take me!
I just want to get to the Channel.
Please! Don't!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Please! No. don't!
Stop! Please. don't!
(FERRY HORN BLARES)
(PULSATING)
Catherine!
Something's happening.
What’s going on?
Multiple objects are approaching Earth.
- What sort of objects?
- We don’t know.
They’re travelling
at over 1000 km a second.
That’s impossible.
What?
I can't.
(MADELINE SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
(PULSATING)
(GASPS)
(PULSATING GROWS LOUDER)
They’re losing speed.
They’re slowing
as they enter the atmosphere.
Do you think it’s...
an attack?
(OBJECTS VIBRATING)
Mum!
(GLASS SHATTERS)
What's going on?
I don't know.
What is that?
(RUMBLING)
What's that?
Is that a meteor?
Impact in 80 seconds.
Shouldn't we do something?
MOKRANI: Do what?
What the fuck is that?
Emily...
Emily!
Emily. what are you doing?
Can't you feel it?
Get inside!
Impact in 10 seconds.
Six. five. four. three. two...
Multiple impacts reported.
Initial assessments suggest
minimal and localised damage.
- Saaid. reports every 10 minutes.
- Yes. sir.
-  For all the impacted sites.
-  Understood.
REPORTER 1:
Last night's attacks have sent
fearful tremors across the globe.
REPORTER 2: ...volunteers are working
around the clock to rescue six...
REPORTER 3: Reports suggest
upward of 2500 objects...
(NEWS REPORTS OVERLAPPING)
NEWSREADER: (ON RADIO)
The government has responded
by declaring a state of emergency.
Schools have been closed
and all civilian aircraft are
grounded until further notice...
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
UK COMMAND & CONTROL CENTRE
We're getting reports of rioting in
London. Manchester and Birmingham.
There's severe congestion on
all routes out of major cities.
It's only gonna get worse.
We need to get the message out.
People should stay in
their own homes.
It's the safest place for them to be.
I'll get on it.
Your family are here.
It's just a precaution.
until things calm down.
Keep me updated.
(SIREN WAILS)
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRR)
How are you. sis?
I just want to know you’re okay.
I know you don’t want to talk.
but text me at least
to let me know you’re okay.
Please.
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(DOOR BANGS SHUT)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE REVS)
TEAM LEADER: (ON RADIO)
Can you hear us? Alpha Team. come in.
(RADIO STATIC)
Radioactivity levels are normal.
Testing negative
for chemical and biological agents.
(GRUNTS)
We're detecting
a strong electromagnetic field.
Flux density...
(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
COMMANDING OFFICER:
Alpha Team. we've lost visual.
TEAM LEADER:
It's interfering with our comms.
There's some kind of metallic object.
(VOICE DISTORTED)
COMMANDING OFFICER:
Alpha Team. can you identify?
Alpha Team. come in.
TEAM LEADER: I'd say it's partially
embedded in the ground.
TEAM LEADER: It's spherical.
non-porous. Metallic object.
TEAM LEADER:
Confirm you're getting this.
COMMANDING OFFICER:
Alpha Team. come in.
(RADIO STATIC)
TEAM LEADER: I repeat.
radioactivity levels normal.
Negative chemical.
biological agents.
Strong electromagnetic field.
Object...
..metallic. spherical. non-porous.
Partially embedded.
(LINE RINGS)
For fuck’s sake. answer your phone.
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
Sophia?
Why do you keep calling me?
Listen. I know things aren’t great
between us right now
but you should come to the observatory.
-Why?
- It’s safer here.
Do you think
these things are dangerous?
I don’t know. I don’t know.
Please... come.
For once. trust me.
But I don’t understand.
What’s happening?
- Do you have petrol in your car?
- Yes.
- Tell me what’s happening.
- Don’t take anything. just leave. Now.
Catherine. you’re scaring me...
Sophia... Sophia.
I beg you.
Okay.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(SIGHS)
People are getting out of London.
so maybe I should go to my dad's
until we know what's happening.
Yeah. you should. you should go.
The Channel Tunnel's still open. so
I'm gonna see if I can get a train.
and I'm gonna meet you at dad's
as soon as I can. okay?
Sarah...
Just be careful.
Okay. Bye.
It is pretty cool.
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS AND VIBRATES)
REPORTER: (ON TV) ...scientists
have been working tirelessly
to extract samples
from the surface of the object.
Bill?
(ON PHONE) Er... hi. Helen.
I just wanted to check
and see that you were okay.
These things last night.
God. it's insane.
Helen?
Bill. one of the neighbours
saw you
hanging around the apartment
last night.
(SCOFFS) Geez. I was just passing by.
Was it that crazy old bitch
with the shitty dog?
She never liked me.
You know it's her dog
that craps in the hallway.
It is not appropriate for you
to just show up here.
What is it you want? What do you
think's gonna happen with us?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
Him. again?
I'm gonna talk to him.
He's just worried.
It's not his job
to worry about you.
REPORTER: (ON MONITOR)
The most significant discovery so far
is that of astrophysicists in Brazil.
who were the first to observe
concentrated electromagnetic activity
at their local probe site.
Several sources have now...
The first samples show
at least four unknown chemical elements.
What’s generating
the electromagnetic field?
All we know is that the signals’ frequency
and amplitude are continuing to increase.
We send probes to other planets
to study them. It’s only logical.
They might do the same to us.
But why send so many?
And why are they clustered
around population centres?
The original signal...
We picked it up during
one rotation of the Earth.
And?
It’s the time needed to do
a complete scan of our planet.
They were mapping us?
Do you think we should destroy them?
They could be weapons.
Saaid. show us the images
from Wyoming.
Look. An F-16 dropped
a one-tonne bomb on one of them.
Direct hit and not even a scratch.
Catherine...
My. er. parents absolutely
want me to be with them.
So. I'll stay if you want me to
of course. but...
You should go.
Okay.
Bye.
MAN: (ON MONITOR) Expert analysis
indicates the probes are emitting
an electromagnetic field.
though little is understood
of its purpose.
Scientists around the world are
caught up in a fervent debate
as to the implications.
but no conclusive answers
have been found thus far.
There is still widespread
speculation as to the cause
of the dropouts
in power shortages.
mobile communications...
Hey. Tony. it's Bill.
Listen. Tony.
I need the results of your
sub-retinal stimulation study.
(ON PHONE) They should be
on the shared hard drive.
On the shared hard drive?
Okay. thanks. I'll talk to you later.
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
Dad?
Dan. you gotta talk to the Minister.
Dad. slow down.
No. you gotta listen to me. Dan.
The electromagnetic fields
these probes are emitting.
I think it's designed to interfere
with our neural functioning.
They're identical to the pulses
we use to stimulate neurons
in the brain.
It's the exact same frequency
and amplitude. Everything.
It's almost like
they understand our neurology.
How is it that even possible?
I don't know.
But as the pulse gets stronger.
it's gonna cause more and more
neurons to fire.
It'll cause seizures and our bodies
will shut down completely.
Are you sure?
Sure as I can be.
People need to get somewhere
completely encased in metal
or deep underground.
Dan. you have to get the government
to issue a warning.
Okay. I'll...
I'll speak to the Minister.
(RINGS)
REPORTER: With public transport
suspended for the foreseeable future.
major roads leading to the capital
continue to be gridlocked
despite government pleas
for people to stay at home.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
Shit!
(SIGHS IN EXASPERATION)
(CHAIR THUDS)
He says we'll start to fit. that our
bodies will completely shut down.
Our scientists are saying
the same thing.
They've been running tests
at Porton Down.
What? You knew?
Don't we need to issue an alert?
We can't issue a warning until
we're sure. We can't risk mass panic.
What if it's too late?
Dan. the decision's been made. okay?
We wait.
(PEOPLE TALK INDISTINCTLY)
Taxi! Taxi!
Come on!
(HORNS HONK)
-	The train station. please.
-	I’m not working.
Please. I really have to get to...
Get out of my taxi.
Just take...take this. please.
Just go.
Okay. thank you.
(SIRENS WAIL)
(PEOPLE SHOUT INDISTINCTLY)
(POLICEMAN BLOWS WHISTLE)
SARAH: They're turning people around.
What do we do?
Maybe we should just go home.
I thought you said
it wasn't safe there.
I'm not sure we've got much choice.
Things might calm down later.
We can try again.
Text Dad.
Let him know we're going home.
Okay.
(PULSATING)
What is that?
Can you feel something?
What?
There's this sound.
I heard it last night.
(PULSATING CONTINUES)
Can't you hear it?
No.
It's so weird.
(PEOPLE TALK INDISTINCTLY)
(KEYBOARD CLACKS RAPIDLY)
Come on. come on.
(POLICE SIREN WAILS)
Excuse me...excuse me. Is there
another route we could take?
Okay. er...
Okay. this is all I've got.
Just get me there.
(ENGINE REVS)
(EXHALES)
What the fuck is that?
What is it?
What is that?
The effect of the electromagnetic field
on the atmosphere.
It looks bad.
Sir. the British government has issued
a warning of an imminent attack.
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
They're saying
there's gonna be an attack.
Who?
It's the government's Twitter feed.
They're telling people to find
shelter. to get underground.
What should we do?
I don't know.
Mum!
I don't know!
(GUNSHOTS. PEOPLE SCREAM)
Why are they shooting at people?
I'm sure they're just firing into
the air. They're warning shots.
Your voice changes when you lie.
(GUNSHOTS. PEOPLE SCREAM)
(PEOPLE SHOUT INDISTINCTLY)
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
- Hello?
- It’s me. Where are you?
In the valley but I’m stuck in traffic.
Listen to me. There’s going to be an attack.
You have to take shelter.
- What do you mean. an attack?
-1 don’t know. You need to get underground.
-  Just go!
-  But there’s nowhere to go.
(AIRCRAFT ENGINES ROAR)
Oh. shit.
(SIREN WAILS)
(BEEPING)
Chris?
Bill?
What are you doing here?
I've got to find Helen.
No. she doesn't want to see you.
You know that. You don't
understand.
There's an attack.
No. you've got to calm down.
It's happening. We don't have time.
(GRUNTS)
Oh. Jesus.
EMILY: Mum!
Mum. what should we do?
(BANG)
Mum...
Do something!
Mum!
(ENGINE REVS. TYRES SCREECH)
(HORN HONKS)
Slow down!
(TYRES SCREECH)
Shit!
Mum!
What was that?
Mum. why are you going so quickly?
(TYRES SCREECH. HORN HONKS)
Get out! Get out!
Get into the station!
Helen. open up!
Come on.
What are you doing here?
Come with me right now.
Come or you're going to die.
Come with you where?
To the elevator.
It'll protect us against
the electromagnetic field.
Have you seen Chris?
Uh...no. I haven't.
Get in the elevator now.
We have to find Chris first.
We don't have time.
What are you doing? Get off.
No. stop! Chris! Chris!
You gotta come with me.
Chris! We gotta get Chris.
Chris! Chris!
(PEOPLE YELL)
- I’m sorry for being such a screw-up.
- No. that’s not true.
I never call you back. I’m a screw-up.
You’re always there for me.
- Don’t say that. Just get underground.
- But there’s nowhere.
- The things I said to you. I’m sorry.
- Go! Find shelter underground. now.
There’s nothing!
There’s nowhere to go.
Sir...
We've lost contact with our aircraft.
They’re all dropping off.
(THUD)
Something’s happening.
Hello?
Sophia... Sophia!
Hello!
Sir...
What’s happening?
We need a connection. Quick!
(ALARM BLARES)
Quick! Come on!
(PEOPLE SHOUT)
(CAR ALARMS BLARE)
How long till we get there?
We have to find
a way out of the Bank.
No. no! Watch out!
(TYRES SCREECH)
(SCREAMING)
(HORN HONKS)
(TYRES SCREECH)
(THUDDING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(PANTS)
(BREATHES RAPIDLY)
Come on!
(BANGS DOOR)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
Chris!
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Saaid. make sure
all the doors stay closed.
- Do you think it’s over?
-1 don’t know.
Everyone! Save your batteries.
Switch off your torches.
(SOLDIERS SPEAK INDISTINCTLY)
(THUDDING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHS)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(PANTS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(EXHALES)
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org